# Furkan Alioglu

**✓** furkanalioglu@gmail.com | **→** +90 553 616 1996 | **♥** Levent, Istanbul, Turkey

in linkedin.com/in/furkanalioglu | ■ medium.com/@furkanalioglu | • github.com/furkanalioglu

## Summary

Senior iOS Developer specialized in Swift, SwiftUI, and React Native (iOS). Experience with large-scale apps reaching \$500K MRR. Content creator with 100,000+ monthly views on Medium and LinkedIn. Strong expertise in MetalPetal, CoreML, WebSocket, and SnapKit.

### Education

## Yildiz Technical University

Istanbul, Turkey

Statistics

2021

• Ranked in the top 0.9% among 2.3 million entrants of the Turkish Higher Education Selection Exam (YKS)

# Experience

## Volvox Mobile x Teknasyon

Istanbul, Turkey

Senior iOS Developer

2023 - Present

- Scaled Cikcik, an iOS live chat application with millions of users and 2TB of daily data flow, increasing MRR from \$30K to \$500K within two years
- Integrated live streaming module using **Agora** and optimized architecture to increase **average stream duration** from 4 hours to 12 hours by moving operations from CPU to GPU with **Metal**
- Improved app crash-free rate from 95% to 99.8% using Firebase Crashlytics and Sentry
- Implemented Xcode Cloud to accelerate testing processes and utilized macros to improve Xcode project workflow efficiency by 60%

Hustler Engine Remote

iOS Developer

January 2022 - January 2023

- Developed 5+ macOS and iOS applications using Swift and SwiftUI, resulting in client satisfaction and many contract renewals
- Managed developer-customer relationships with many clients across Europe and increased project delivery speed
- Created a custom Swift Package Manager (SPM) infrastructure that **reduced development time**, enabling release of a **new app every three weeks**

**SpeecherAI** 

Founder

Istanbul, Turkey

January 2021 – January 2022

- Founded and built Speecher AI, achieving many organic download in first month
- Developed one of the first SwiftUI apps on the App Store
- Conducted ASO and marketing experiments with A/B tests

#### Technical Skills

Languages: Swift, Objective-C, React Native

Frameworks & Libraries: SwiftUI, UIKit, Combine, Core Data, Metal, SnapKit, Auto Layout, SPM, GCD, REST APIs, WebSockets, Alamofire, Moya, Firebase, Agora, RevenueCat, OneSignal, Amplitude, AppsFlyer

Architecture: MVC, MVVM, MVVM-C, VIPER

Tools: Xcode, Xcode Cloud, Git, GitFlow, Firebase Crashlytics, Sentry, MetalPetal, CoreML

#### Content Creation

**Technical Writer** | Medium & LinkedIn

2021 - Present

• Publish up-to-date, high-quality iOS development content receiving 100,000+ monthly views

## Languages & Additional Information

Turkish: Native English: Fluent

**Travel & Work Eligibility**: Turkish Green Passport holder, visa-free travel to Europe for up to 180 days/year.